Kate Parkin

Senior geologist with 13 years' experience in development, exploration and new ventures. Strong background in development geology and near-field appraisal, generating field development plans and well proposals. Experienced in conventional plays in a range of geological settings in West and North Africa. Recent focus on exploration and resource assessment of emerging onshore UK unconventional plays. Excellent communication skills and team-working within multinational, multidisciplinary teams. Qualified EFL teacher with strong planning, preparation and presentation skills.

Key Skills

- 3D geological modelling
- Generation of FDPs and well proposals (Development / Appraisal / Exploration)
- HIIP estimation
- Bid round evaluations and risking
- Well operations: well planning to post-well analysis
- Petrophysical interpretation
- TCMs / partner workshops / peer reviews
- Government / public engagement

- Cameroon: Niger Delta (RdR Basin), Douala Basin
- Gabon: North Gabon Basin
- Algeria/Tunisia/Libya: Ghadames Basin
- UK: Onshore
- Turbidites, deltaics / marginal marine
- Unconventional / hybrid plays
- Extensional to compressional regimes, shale diapirism, salt basins
- Petrel, IP, Geolog, ArcGIS, DM

Employment

• EFL teaching, independent travelling

2017 – present

- Teaching English as a foreign language at Link School, London and Language Link London to mixed and mono-lingual groups from juniors to adults of all abilities and one-to-one tuition carrying out needs analysis, syllabus planning and lesson preparation and delivery. Volunteer teaching in rural schools in Nepal.
- Self-taught web design creating a professional tour company website
- Self-supported cycle touring and trekking across India, Nepal and SE Asia

• Senior Geologist, Unconventionals Team – IGas Plc.

2014 - 2017

UK (Onshore)

- Regional exploration studies focused on the unconventional potential of onshore UK assets creating large scale 3D models for volumetric analysis and sweet spot mapping adding over 100 Tcf of resources and multiple drilling opportunities
- Integration of detailed biostratigraphy, geochemistry, outcrop, geological facies, rock typing, geomechanical and fracture modelling studies
- Shale petrophysical analysis
- Onshore UK 14th Licensing Round assessment resulting in the acquisition of acreage with conventional, unconventional and hybrid potential
- Leading well proposals and data acquisition programmes for unconventional targets (2 key targets subsequently drilled) and work programmes for unconventional acreage
- Overseeing well operations for exploration well EP-1; daily reporting and liaising with rigsite and drilling team, onsite ops and decision making at critical phases, and post-well analyses
- Mentoring junior geologists and supervising MSc students
- Frequent participation in TCMs and partner workshops, peer reviews and assists
- Interaction with local council, UK government authorities (OGA) and public engagement

Senior Geologist, Geosciences Team - Perenco

2007 - 2014

Cameroon (Niger Delta – Rio del Rey Basin, Douala Basin)

- Development geology of offshore assets building 3D structural and geological models integrating geological, geophysical, petrophysical and production data
- Creating FDPs e.g. Dissoni field (15000 bopd) and Sanaga Sud (20000 mscfd)

- Well proposal generation including near field appraisal and exploration targets (10 wells drilled in three years, 6 wells scheduled)
- Assessment of remaining opportunities in mature basins, including building prospect inventories (2 block-wide studies resulting in ~400 MMbbls resources)
- Deltaic/marginal marine systems in extensional to compressional regimes; shale diapirism
- Technical supervision of geological studies and reservoir modeling in subsidiary offices
- New venture evaluations (datarooms in international sites covering Cameroon, Colombia, Peru)

Gabon (North Gabon Basin)

- Integrated development and appraisal studies of clastic turbidite systems in a salt basin resulting in additional drilling and production (4 wells with ~2000 bopd incremental production)
- Successful appraisal of offshore discoveries e.g. LCME-3, initial rate 750 bopd

Operations Geologist

 Responsible for overseeing well operations for West African exploration, appraisal and development wells; including well proposal and design, evaluation programmes, daily reporting and liaising with rigsite, decision making on casing and coring points and post-well analyses

Geologist, International Onshore Exploration – Anadarko

2004 - 2007

- Responsible for the geology of onshore Algeria acreage evaluating prospects and leads and appraising discoveries within the continental clastic TAGI formation
- Basin modeling, assessing charge and migration for new venture opportunities, including offshore Libya and Tunisia and the Black Sea
- Geological support during Algerian and Libyan licensing rounds

Internship - BP, Sunbury

2002

Quality filtering seismic and well data for integration into a Global Information Database

• Laboratory Technician - ERT Caspian, Baku, Azerbaijan

1998 - 1999

Analysis of offshore samples for EIAs in the Caspian in support of regional operations

Education

MSc Petroleum Geoscience (Distinction), Imperial College

2002 - 2003

 Thesis: Anadarko Ourhoud development team. Characterizing and mapping a high porosity-low permeability interval within the TAGI Formation in the Ghadames Basin, Algeria. Awarded the London Petrophysical Society prize

BSc Exploration Geology (2:1), University of Wales, Cardiff

1999 - 2002

Thesis: Mapping base metal mineralization using extensive fieldwork and geochemical data

Other Skills & Interests

- CELTA (Certificate in English Language Teaching to Adults) (Pass B, March 2018)
- BSc in Molecular Science (2:1, 2013), with the Open University
- Intermediate French language skills

Personal Details